<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<requests>
    <item>
        <title>CRC hash checking ability for MD5 checker. - ID: 1829324</title>
        <detail>I don't know if its possible to implement, but maybe its a good idea to implement CRC functionality for MD5 checker. (MS has crc hashes (eg. at vs express)). 
 
 
Best Regards!!! :-)</detail>
        <time>gk67 ( elf_wizard  ) - 2007-11-09 16:16:48 PST</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>AMSN - ID: 1994742</title>
        <detail>It would be great if you added AMSN messenger. 
 
Thanks</detail>
        <time>Emilio Haneine Marbez ( pucaleco  ) - 2008-06-15 20:25:40 PDT</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Programs available in Greek (let me translate them) - ID: 2914383</title>
        <detail>I can translate any programs on this project in Greek so you will add one more language!</detail>
        <time>DaKnObCS ( daknob  ) - 2009-12-14 12:33:04 PST</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>RetroShare Messenger Portable - ID: 1738614</title>
        <detail>http://retroshare.sf.net 
 
is a serverless encrtypted Messenger and Email system 
 
please make it portable 
 
Here is a script already: 
http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=178712&amp;package_id=206218&amp;release_id=512453</detail>
        <time>Nobody/Anonymous ( nobody  ) - 2007-06-17 04:54:09 PDT</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Portable 7-Zip, ClamAV, Foxit, VideoLAN - ID: 1362916</title>
        <detail>Dear John, 
 
first of all many thanks for contributing such useful 
Open Source programs to the community! 
Therefore I updated and added some program listings at 
betanews.com for you. 
 
With Portable OpenOffice.org I already can view and 
edit most document formats on every PC or laptop just 
by plugging in my USB thumbdrive. 
I can convert incompatible Word, Excel and Powerpoint 
files to standard OpenDocument formats and then export 
them easily into the Portable Document Format (PDF). 
 
But what about four other important file format types: 
archive, multimedia, PDF and virus files? 
 
Now that Google supports Firefox, Gaim and VideoLAN, 
these already good alternatives have the power to 
become standard programs. 
 
With Portable VideoLAN I could take most multimedia 
files AND a player on my USB thumbdrive and could watch 
and listen them on every PC. 
http://planet.videolan.org/ 
http://www.videolan.org/vlc/ 
 
 
7-Zip is one of the best archive programs, it extracts 
many archive formats and creates extremely high 
compressed 7z archives. 
Even the popular WinRAR supports 7z archives already. 
 
With Portable 7-Zip I could compress everything I need 
to transport with my USB thumbdrive to very small 7z 
files and could extract them on every PC. 
Every week and every new Portable App means less free 
space on my USB thumbdrive. 
http://sourceforge.net/forum/forum.php?thread_id=1280551&amp;forum_id=45797 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/7-zip 
 
 
ClamAV is a powerful and cross platform anti virus program. 
 
With Portable ClamAV every normal PC user could test 
every computer he is working with BEFORE he works with it. 
The first thing he has to do is just plugging in his 
USB thumbdrive and let Portable ClamAV automatically 
scan memory, boot sectors and all hard disk files. 
http://www.bransoft.com/clammail/clammail.html 
http://www.clamwin.net/ 
http://www.clamav.net/3rdparty.html#gui 
 
An alternative to ClamAV would be AVG Anti-Virus, but 
it's only Freeware, not Open Source. 
It is strongly supported by Intel and has a very good 
scanning engine. 
http://www.grisoft.com/doc/314/lng/us/tpl/tpl01 
 
 
And instead of downloading and installing the 23 MB 
Adobe Reader when I want to view the standard PDF files 
generated by Portable OpenOffice.org, it would be much 
easier just to start the free and small Foxit Reader 
right from my iPod. 
http://www.foxitsoftware.com/pdf/rd_intro.php 
This program is Freeware, too. 
 
 
I could convince all people of these great programs 
without forcing them to install anything onto their 
computers. 
Just by plugging my thumbdrive in and showing them the 
power of Open Source. 
 
 
Best regards, 
Ren¨¦</detail>
        <time>Rene Leonhardt ( rele  ) - 2005-11-21 08:47:43 PST</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Apps that run on multiple platforms - ID: 2943252</title>
        <detail>Hello, 
 
I'm the admin of DocFetcher, a desktop-search app written in Java, which is hosted on SourceForge.net as well. Currently, we have a portable version which is capable of running on both Windows and Linux, provided that a Java Runtime is installed. On Windows, the program is launched with an Exe, on Linux with a shell script. 
 
We'd like to make this portable version Portable Apps compatible. However, after having skimmed your docs, I have the impression that Portable Apps are generally Windows-only. Is this correct? And if so, are there any plans to support programs that run on multiple platforms, especially Java programs? 
 
Best regards 
q:-) &lt;= Tran Nam Quang</detail>
        <time>Tran Nam Quang ( qforce  ) - 2010-01-31 07:28:43 PST</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Media Player Classic - ID: 3173343</title>
        <detail>add media player classic</detail>
        <time>Alex Leard ( ffpoke  ) - 2011-02-04 23:59:18 PST</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Localized websites and downloads - ID: 1369088</title>
        <detail>Hello, 
 
I made some short signatures for your portable apps. 
 
Edit Office documents on every PC or Laptop: Portable 
OpenOffice.org 
With your own preferences, templates, dictionaries. 
Without installation. Free. 
http://portableoo.sourceforge.net/ 
 
Surf the Web with your own browser on every PC, even in 
Internet Caf¨¦s: Portable Firefox 
With all your preferences, bookmarks, passwords, 
extensions. Without installation. Free. 
http://portablefirefox.sourceforge.net/ 
 
Chat with your own messenger on every PC, even in 
Internet Caf¨¦s: Portable Gaim 
With all your preferences, passwords, logs. Without 
installation. Free. 
http://portablegaim.sourceforge.net/ 
 
1) portablegaim.sourceforge.net should redirect to 
http://johnhaller.com/jh/useful_stuff/portable_gaim/ 
instead of 
http://johnhaller.com/jh/development/portable_apps/ 
 
2) There should be localized project pages and 
downloads, too. 
 
I would love to translate them to german. 
 
 
Keep up the good work, 
Ren¨¦po</detail>
        <time>Rene Leonhardt ( rele  ) - 2005-11-29 03:59:53 PST</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Portable Mame - ID: 1748685</title>
        <detail>Mame emulator or mame capability.</detail>
        <time>Nobody/Anonymous ( nobody  ) - 2007-07-05 11:59:05 PDT</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Add Portable Registry Tool - ID: 1898155</title>
        <detail>It would be nice if there was a portable registry tool that could be used with the portable application suite. It would be nice if the registry tool was similar to Reg, but portable. http://sourceforge.net/projects/reg/ 
 
like the ability to do a search for keyword and delete all in one shot.</detail>
        <time>LKDC ( lkdc  ) - 2008-02-20 12:34:54 PST</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Recognise preinstalled applications - ID: 1959850</title>
        <detail>For various reasons it is possible for someone to install potentially all the offered applications, which takes a large amount of time, and have customized them all as needed, before they needed or wanted to install the menu program. Because of this possibility the menu program should have the ability to find or be shown applications that have already been installed, then add them to the list.</detail>
        <time>Greys ( greys0  ) - 2008-05-07 15:46:49 PDT</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>SNES Emulator - ID: 1765614</title>
        <detail>Would be very nice to have a Super Nintendo emulator (also know as Famicon if I'm no wrong) ^^</detail>
        <time>Nobody/Anonymous ( nobody  ) - 2007-08-01 10:42:30 PDT</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Add other programs - ID: 1777216</title>
        <detail>Would like the ability to add programs to the apps list. Basically I have some apps there are .jar or run from .bat files that I would like to add. It would also give the ability to launch the same program with different command line arguments. 
 
Somewhat similar to: 1670190</detail>
        <time>Jim ( jchiang  ) - 2007-08-19 08:13:54 PDT</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Ability to add programs in sub folders - ID: 1670190</title>
        <detail>I would like to be able to add a program to the menu that is in a sub folder. When I PortableApps\newprogram\subfloder\program.exe It will not show up on menu.  I've copied the exe to just the newprogram folder and it shows up but will not run, it has to be in its specific folder to work.  If you could also add support for batch files to show up on the menu that would be great too.  Thanks for all the work you've done so far I love Portableapps.</detail>
        <time>Nobody/Anonymous ( nobody  ) - 2007-02-27 09:51:17 PST</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Recent Programs view - ID: 2857970</title>
        <detail>This feature gives the opportunity to the user to see the programs that he has recently use and he can open it directly. If there are many programs install on the Portable Software/USB this feature will be very helpful for the user.   
 
I attach the file use case for recent programs view.</detail>
        <time>Marios Ioannou ( mioannou  ) - 2009-09-13 02:57:22 PDT</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>ability to create sub-menus - ID: 1972684</title>
        <detail>I would like to have sub-menus to group for instance the OpenOffice applications and the system tools.  
I use a lot of the provided applications so I have to scroll a lot. Sub-menus would make it easier.</detail>
        <time>PeHo ( nl06088  ) - 2008-05-26 04:10:53 PDT</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>FindProcDll and Latent Error - ID: 1598327</title>
        <detail>Hi, Dear Project Developer, 
 
After reading the code of FindProcDLL, i found that it is considered DANGEROUS that we use &quot;pop $R0&quot; command to get the return value. Because FindProcDLL will write the return value DIRECTLY to $R0 instead of pushing the return value to stack. 
 
This may cause problem when you leave some data in the stack. 
 
A nice solution is to use a macro to wrap FindProcDLL::FindProc function. 
 
 
; =====MACRO-BLOCK-START===== 
!macro FindProc _RETURN_VAR _PROC_NAME 
  Push $R0 ; [STACK] &lt;&lt; $R0 
  FindProcDLL::FindProc &quot;${_PROC_NAME}&quot; 
  Exch $R0 ; [STACK] &lt;&lt; [RETURN_VALUE] 
  Pop ${_RETURN_VAR} ; ${_RETURN_VAR} = [RETURN_VALUE] 
!macroend 
!define FindProc &quot;!insertmacro FindProc&quot; 
; =====MACRO-BLOCK-END===== 
 
 
And use command: 
 
; =====CODE-EXAMPLE-BLOCK-START===== 
${FindProc} [RETURN_VALUE] [PROC_NAME] 
;e.g. ${FindProc} $R0 &quot;firefox.exe&quot; 
; =====CODE-EXAMPLE-BLOCK-END===== 
 
 
Hope this is helpful! 
 
Regards, 
_______________hobbyscripter</detail>
        <time>hobbyscripter ( hobbyscripter  ) - 2006-11-17 04:16:02 PST</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>ability to update included applications - ID: 1964524</title>
        <detail>This would be very nice if we could update applications installed before.</detail>
        <time>baterist ( baterist  ) - 2008-05-15 05:09:09 PDT</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Automatic Update - ID: 2945973</title>
        <detail>Automatic Update include installed sub program</detail>
        <time>MIX THE WIZARD ( mix5003  ) - 2010-02-04 06:45:40 PST</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Ability to Change Displayed App Name - ID: 1614096</title>
        <detail>Since the displayed application name seems to come from the application itself, and there is no XML file or INI file to edit, there is no way to customize the names of apps on the PA menu.  My suggestion is to provide an XML file that lists the default names, but that would allow updating; or a file that maps the default name to a custom name, so that if that app doesn't have an entry, it simply uses the default name.</detail>
        <time>Nobody/Anonymous ( nobody  ) - 2006-12-12 08:37:57 PST</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Portable SSH Client - ID: 1370508</title>
        <detail>Dear Mr. Haller, 
 
I greatly appreciate the effort you have gone to in 
creating the Portable Apps suite.  I use both 
PortableFirefox and PortableFirezilla every day.  One 
application I would personally like to see added to the 
suite is a portable SSH client such as PuTTY.  PuTTY is 
both open source and portable, but saves all settings 
and configuration information locally.  It would be 
tremendously helpful and time-saving to have all the 
settings save to a portable device.  Once again, thank 
you for your contribution to the open source community! 
 
Sincerely, 
 
Joseph Sturtevant</detail>
        <time>Joseph Sturtevant ( sturtevant  ) - 2005-11-30 17:10:32 PST</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Portable Image Editor - ID: 1382318</title>
        <detail>Thise is a VERY cool project i like it wery much. 
 
I like to see a Image Editor in thise to. 
 
The problem for me is coming to a place where the dont 
have a image editor, only windows &quot;paint&quot; and that not 
always good enough. 
 
I can see some people working on GIMP portable, but it 
hasent been realese yet. 
https://sourceforge.net/projects/portablegimp/ 
But when it do it could be add to or what? 
Or any other now a good portable Editor!</detail>
        <time>Jan Boesgaard ( lordrebuse  ) - 2005-12-16 02:24:01 PST</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Program Request - ID: 1786161</title>
        <detail>Please add Opera Portable and an Engineering Graphing  
Calculator to this selection. 
Thanks</detail>
        <time>Nobody/Anonymous ( nobody  ) - 2007-08-31 21:54:53 PDT</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>7-ZIP Portable 4.43 - ID: 1737764</title>
        <detail>Hello, 
 
Thank you for very nice programs. 
 
I would like to encurage you to make 7-ZIP 4.47beta  avaliable as portable app. 
 
The ZIP, AES support is a great feature for a portable app. since it's mostly on portable media you want to use encryption? 
 
The speed optimizations should also be good. 
 
/Magnus</detail>
        <time>Nobody/Anonymous ( nobody  ) - 2007-06-15 04:08:19 PDT</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Skinning feature/ eject button - ID: 1721639</title>
        <detail>can we get a skinning feature? we could have black or blue! 
 
or at least a eject button like in u3</detail>
        <time>Nobody/Anonymous ( nobody  ) - 2007-05-18 20:51:04 PDT</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Support for Abyss Web Server X1 - ID: 1948071</title>
        <detail>Hello, 
 
I very much like your XAMPP launcher for portableapps. 
 
However, I am using the free Abyss Web Server X1 (http://www.aprelium.com/abyssws/) because I have found it easier to install ASP and ASP.NET support on this web server. It also has a very neat control panel. I was pulling my hair out with XAMPP! 
 
Therefore I would like to ask you clever developers if you would kindly develop an Abyss launcher for the portable apps menu. If you're too short of time, would you please then consider integrating support for Abyss in the XAMPP launcher. 
 
Thank you for the XAMPP launcher and please do consider creating a small launcher for Abyss (just to start/stop Apache and MySQL). 
 
Kind regards, 
Olivier</detail>
        <time>wifigoo ( olivierdb  ) - 2008-04-21 09:23:42 PDT</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>GUI Editing - ID: 1679551</title>
        <detail>Is there any way that the end user would be able to change the color scheme for the app, in a way that is easy to figure out without having to rebuild the entire app?</detail>
        <time>Nobody/Anonymous ( nobody  ) - 2007-03-12 21:59:18 PDT</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Portable SeaMonkey - ID: 1486176</title>
        <detail>I'm not sure if anyone else would be interested in a 
portable version of SeaMonkey, but I much prefer the 
suite to the individual programs from Mozilla.  I would 
love to see a portable version, and have a SeaMonkey 
Suite installer as well as the Firefox\Thunderbird 
Suite installer (basically, have the Portable Apps 
Suite with SeaMonkey instead of FF\TB).</detail>
        <time>Nobody/Anonymous ( nobody  ) - 2006-05-10 21:34:40 PDT</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Ability to Hide Apps - ID: 1614094</title>
        <detail>I have Portable Opera on my thumbdrive, and when I put that app's folder into the PortableApps folder, not only does Opera's application show up on the PA menu, but an app called GASR shows up as well.  Since it's part of the Portable Opera folder, I can't remove it, so I'm stuck with it showing or I have to remove the menu item for Opera.</detail>
        <time>Nobody/Anonymous ( nobody  ) - 2006-12-12 08:35:24 PST</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>new program: Miro - ID: 2814302</title>
        <detail>It would be great if you could bring a portable version of Miro HD Video Player http://www.getmiro.com/ 
which is an Open Source internet TV viewer</detail>
        <time>Salvador Calderon ( scintnl  ) - 2009-06-29 17:10:41 PDT</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Icon  - ID: 3576142</title>
        <detail>When you install Portable Apps to a thumb drive, it changes the thumbdrive icon to portable apps, it would be nice to have an option to remove it.  
 
Love this so useful</detail>
        <time>julien croy  ( legacy28  ) - 2012-10-10 15:03:08 PDT</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Ability to lauch apps on startup - ID: 1681830</title>
        <detail>Add the ability to have a program launch on startup of the PA menu.</detail>
        <time>Glenn ( grapps  ) - 2007-03-15 20:28:17 PDT</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Easier Uninstall - ID: 3406234</title>
        <detail>Just as you have added the ability to auto update, and to select new apps, can you add an option to the Manage Menu to uninstall apps. 
This form would be much like the add new from, but all the check-boxes would be checked, and unchecking them would uninstall. 
Of course the check-box operation could be reversed, only check the ones to be uninstalled. 
 
This would make it easier for me to try out and then remove beta/testing versions. Right now, I have to remove the libreoffice test, which is older than the release version.</detail>
        <time>Lawrence Sproul ( sproulster  ) - 2011-09-08 06:19:41 PDT</time>
    </item>
</requests>
