<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<requests>
    <item>
        <title>support for new xorg release which deprecated xfs  - ID: 2504808</title>
        <detail>Hi , subject says all , news xorg don't use xfs anymore could you please do a package that use the new structure of fonts for xorg .  
 
Thanks,</detail>
        <time>S¨¦rgio Monteiro Basto ( sergiomb  ) - 2009-01-13 07:44:10 PST</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Include Vista fonts - ID: 1738684</title>
        <detail>Cambria, Calibri, Candara, Consolas, Constantia, Corbel fonts from Windows Vista typeface can be included using a &quot;Microsoft Office Compatibility Pack for Word, Excel, and PowerPoint 2007 File Formats&quot;</detail>
        <time>aleks ( yaleks  ) - 2007-06-17 08:49:33 PDT</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Addition of Arial Unicode MS - ID: 642759</title>
        <detail>I don't know if the EULA allows it, but if you could make  
Arial Unicode MS (a 23 Mb font featuring tens of  
thousands of glyphs) available, I'd appreciate it very  
much.  Once upon a time, you could get this font from  
MS's website, but no longer it seems.</detail>
        <time>David L. Chandler ( dchandler  ) - 2002-11-23 07:43:08 PST</time>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>An RPM that gets the fonts from the net - ID: 680485</title>
        <detail>I like the way Debian's package works: instead of 
including the fonts directly, which would not be legal, 
and instead of requiring you to make your own package, 
like we have here, they include scripting which uses 
wget and cabextract to actually download the fonts for 
you during the install process. 
 
Thus distributing the package is completely legal, and 
anyone can install it without complicated instructions 
about making your own RPM, etc., because the fonts are 
retrieved dynamically at runtime rather than being 
shipped with the package itself. 
 
 
It seems to me that this kind of RPM, at least as an 
option, would be much easier for people to use. 
 
Just a thought...</detail>
        <time>Paul D. Smith ( psmith  ) - 2003-02-04 13:39:27 PST</time>
    </item>
</requests>
